谢尔顿  再不吃饭都要凉了
Sheldon, your food is getting cold.
我晚点吃
I'll eat later.
现在我在物理母亲的胸前
Right now, I'm suckling at
尽情地允吸知识乳汁呢
the informative bosom of mother physics.
谢尔顿满口荤话时真性感
It's hot when Sheldon talks dirty.
我发现一个网站
So, I found this Web site
只要把自己照片传过去
where you send them pictures,
他们就会雕刻出你的样子
they sculpt your head
然后制作一个像你一样的模型人偶
and make an action figure out of you.
超牛逼的  对不对
How awesome is that?
我看看
Oh, let me see.
服装任你选
Yeah, you can pick your wardrobe.
甚至连配饰都任你选
You can even choose your accessories.
莱纳德  你还可以配一个哮喘吸入器
Leonard, you can get a little asthma inhaler.
这真是太妙了
Oh, this is neat.
想想这些年我们买的模型人偶
Think about all the action figures we've bought over the years.
能拥有像我们自己本人的人偶  还蛮酷的
It would be kind of cool to have ones that look like us.
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
是啊  如果你"酷"的定义是如此
Yeah, if that's your idea of what's cool,
那你真应该买一个
you should get one.
好吧  我不买了
Yeah, so, I'm out.
你觉得呢  谢尔顿
What do you think, Sheldon?
想要一个像你一样的模型人偶吗
Want an action figure that looks just like you?
人偶的手有抓握的功能吗
Would it come with kung-fu grip?
没有
No.
那别浪费我的时间
Don't waste my time.
你懂这是量身定做的独家模型人偶吧
You get that these are personalize action figures.
亲爱的  如果你想要就买吧
Honey, if you want one, just get one.
-你还是不会买的  对吧  -对
-You're still out, right? - Yep.
生活大爆炸 第六季  第十四集
场边群众一片肃静
A hush falls over the crowd
因为库珀在思考
as Cooper studies the board.
他行动了
He makes his move.
他用"I"除以两边
He's dividing both sides by "I."
再加回系数
He's adding back the coefficient.
得到了"P"的值
He has a value for "P."
再将其导回去
He's plugging that back in.
他用导数
He takes the derivative,
解出了该等式
and he solves the equation.
群众们疯狂了
The crowd goes wild.
诺贝尔  诺贝尔
Nobel! Nobel!
库伯
Cooper?
诺贝尔
Nobel.
克莱皮克
Kripke.
不许看我的板子
Don't look at my board.
那是什么
What's that?
一辆超酷的火车
That's a drawing of a really cool train.
那个也不许看
Don't look at that, either.
你来干嘛
What do you want?
我有个坏消息
I have some bad news.
你在申请基金研究关于聚变反应堆
You're working on a grant proposal for a new fusion reactor.
我也在申请基金研究关于聚变反应堆
I'm working on a grant proposal for a new fusion reactor.
而我们大学只允许提交一份申请书
The university is only allowed to submit one proposal.
所以他们让你收拾东西走人啊
So they asked you to pack up your things and ship out.
真是非常遗憾  巴里
That's hard cheese, Barry.
你算是有能力的人之一了
You're one of the good ones.
不  大学的意思是让我们一起合作
No, they're making us work together.
真是太过分了
That's ridiculous.
我可是我们这代伟大的思想家
I am one of the great minds of our generation.
我工作的层次尖端到
I work on a level so rarified
你无法想象
you couldn't even imagine it.
我警告过你  不许看我的火车
I said stop looking at my cool train!
把你和伯纳黛特的合照
Kind of a strange place
挂在这地方  有点奇怪啊
to put a picture of you and Bernadette.
我想让大家知道我爱我老婆
Well, I wanted everybody to know I love my wife.
同时也不想被人知道  我忘了关激光机
And nobody to know I forgot to turn off the laser.
来了
They're here.
我们的模型人偶到了
Our action figures have arrived.
这是我这辈子花过最值的500块
This is the best $500 I've ever spent.
1千块钱买俩人偶
$1,000 on action figures?
你们怎么可能买得起啊
How can you afford that?
简单  他家超有钱
Easy-- his family's loaded,
伯纳黛特的工作超赚钱
and Bernadette has a great job.
怎样  我老婆有胸又有钱
My wife came with both fun bags and money bags.
快来跟我的定制人偶打招呼吧
Say hello to an exact scale model of me.
人家的肤色不是黑巧克力色
Oh, I'm not dark chocolate.
人家是化在嘴里的焦糖色啦
I'm melt-in-your-mouth caramel.
天啊
Oh, man.
瞧我的鼻子
Look at my nose.
或许是送错货了
Maybe it's a shipping problem.
-什么  -对啊
- What? - Yeah.
或许韦斯利·斯奈普斯和大嘴鸟山姆
Maybe Wesley Snipes and Toucan Sam
韦斯利·斯奈普斯  美国黑人男星
大嘴鸟山姆  果脆圈的代表卡通形象
刚收到跟你们俩长得一模一样的模型人偶
just got action figures that look like you guys.
难看死了
This sucks.
真不敢相信老子花了那么多钱
I can't believe I wasted all that money.
可惜我女朋友不让我买啊
Aw, and my girlfriend wouldn't let me get one.
快看我的表情
Look at my face.
是不是洋洋得意  我觉得是哦
Do I look smug? I feel smug.
我恨你让我留下看完片尾的演职员名单
I hate it when you make me sit through all the credits.
有时候电影会在片尾藏有彩蛋啊
Well, sometimes there's a secret ending,
好比《复仇者联盟》
like in The Avengers.
好吧  但我不觉得犹太大屠杀的纪录片
Yeah, but I don't think that's going to happen
会在片尾有什么彩蛋啊
in a documentary about the Holocaust.
可以播点穿帮镜头啊
They could show bloopers.
不要啊
Oh, no.
那是什么声音
What is that?
那是谢尔顿的
That is Sheldon's
"老子不爽  老子要毁了地球"之音
"I'm unhappy and about to destroy the planet" music.
走吧  我们去你家
Come on, let's just go to your place.
别走啊  他不开心  我们不该开导下他吗
Well, wait, if he's unhappy, shouldn't we talk to him?
"我们不该开导下他吗"
"Shouldn't we talk to him?"
你这六年来毛都没学到吗
Have you learned nothing in six years?
你还好吗  亲爱的
You doing okay, sweetie?
这是不祥的背景音乐
There is ominous music playing,
我还像阿富汗人戴头巾
and there is an afghan over my head.
我不知道你打哪儿来的
I don't know where you're from,
但在我老家那边  这代表我很不好
but where I'm from, that means I'm not doing okay.
要不要我给你弄杯茶
Want me to make you some tea?
茶是我不开心时喝的  我又没不开心
Tea is for when I'm upset. I'm not upset.
学校逼我得跟克莱皮克合作
The university's forcing me to work with Kripke.
我现在是气炸了
I'm outraged.
那是泡热可可吗
So, cocoa?
废话  当然是可可
Yes, cocoa.
你们知道那种被迫跟某些
Do you have any idea what it's like to be paired
超惹人厌家伙共处的感觉吗
with someone who's so incredibly annoying?
老师  问我  我知道
Oh, teacher! Me! Me!
我那些超棒的成果
See, I did all this great work,
现在要让他横插一脚  然后毁掉它
and now he's just going to come along and ruin it.
这是我这辈子最气最绝望的时刻了
I am angrier than ever and filled with despair.
这种时候该泡啥给你喝呢
What beverage do you make for that?
等等  等等  我知道的
Oh... no, no, no, I know this.
热苹果汁加肉桂条吗
Hot apple cider with cinnamon sticks?
废话  当然是热苹果汁加肉桂条啦
Yes, hot apple cider with cinnamon sticks!
你搞毛啊  库伯
What the frig, Cooper?
我们不是约好半小时前我办公室见吗
We were supposed to meet in my office a half an hour ago.
但现在是你上我办公室来了
And yet, now you're in my office.
库伯  得一分
Point, Cooper.
欢迎来到竞技场啊  克莱皮克
Welcome to the Thunderdome, Kripke.
我们说好要交换各自的研究
We agreed to exchange copies of our work.
让我看你的
Let me see yours.
你怎么不让我先看你的
Why don't you show me yours first.
你当我第一天出社会啊
You think I just fell off the turnip truck?
我们同时交换
We exchange at the same time.
我怎么知道你不会拿走我的杰作
How do I know you're not going to take my ideas
然后以自己的名义发表呢
and publish them as your own?
那我怎么你不会对我用这招呢
How do I know you're not going to do that with mine?
因为我没兴趣让自己的名字
Yeah, because I'm not interested
出现在某本疯子杂志上
in getting published in Mad magazine.
竞技场里唇枪舌剑很猛烈  脑子要跟上
Zingers fly fast in the Thunderdome, Barry.
到底要不要互换啊
Are we going to do this or not?
谢谢
Thank you.
我们看一遍对方的研究  明天再碰面吧
So, we read each other's work, meet again tomorrow?
行
Fine.
想蒙我啊  这是白纸
Nice try. This is blank paper.
我肯定那也比这里面的内容
And I am sure it's still more valuable
还来得有价值
than whatever's in here.
老实交出来  库伯
Cough it up, Cooper.
好吧
Very well.
这里面要再是白纸  老子一定暴怒
If this one's blank, too, I'm going to be furious.
好啦
Fine.
你
You!
永远要信黑
Always bet on black.
有赌轮盘时  永远下注选黑色  以及信黑人的意思
把那坑钱货从我面前移开
Get that waste of money out of my face.
这玩偶不坑啊
It's only a waste of money
我们不玩才被坑呢
if we don't play with them.
他说的对  兄弟[黑人腔]
He's right, dawg.
别闹了  我在干活
Please, I'm working.
其实还有一个方法  能弄到跟本人一样的
You know, there is a way we can get action figures
模型人偶呢
to look exactly like us.
是吗  说来听听
Oh, yeah? How's that?
两个词  3-D打印机
Two words: 3-D printer.
等等  可能算三个词
Wait, maybe it's three words.
不  让我想想
No, hang on.
好吧  一个词  一个字母  一个数字  以及
Okay, one word, a letter and a number and...
一个连字号吧
maybe a hyphen.
3-D打印机
3-D printer.
我的确想要台3-D打印机很久了
I have always wanted a 3-D printer.
你当然想要啦
Of course you have.
那可是工程师的梦想
They're an engineer's dream.
只要你设计得出
Anything you can design,
那打印机就能用塑料做出实物
a 3-D printer can make out of plastic.
是啊  可是那个超贵呢
Yeah, but they're so expensive.
别这样嘛
Oh, come on.
你值得拥有一台
You deserve one.
你费了那么大的劲才找到一个
You've worked hard to find a woman
超会赚钱的老婆
who makes a lot of money.
那玩意价钱也降下来了
Well, the prices have been coming down.
对啊
Oh, true.
他们现在基本就是白送的了
They're practically giving them away.
只要你给够钱  他就送你
You know, in exchange for money.
我们可以用它做出工作需要的东西
And we can make stuff we need for work with it.
我计算机辅助设计与制造的技术原形
Prototypes of my CAD/CAM designs,
特制的工具
specialized tools...
还有马里布高富帅库萨帕里玩偶
Not to mention Malibu Koothrappali
以及他的超屌梦幻豪宅啦
and his totally bitchin' dream house.
我们才没必要做那豪宅呢
We don't need Malibu Koothrappali's dream house.
是吗  聪明小伙
Really, smart guy?
那他新买的超帅跑车要停哪里啊
Where's he supposed to park his sweet little Corvette?
我烟草实验的猴子已经开始抽烟斗了
The monkey in my tobacco study has taken to smoking a pipe.
按理我应该这时取出他的脑子检验
I'm supposed to remove his brain to examine,
但我做不到  他这样子让我想起我叔叔
but it's hard because now he reminds me of my uncle.
你今晚安静得出奇啊
You've been awfully quiet tonight.
你没事吧
Is everything okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
好吧  那今天工作如何了
All right, well, how was work today?
你跟克莱皮克交换研究报告了吗
Did you exchange your research with Kripke?
交换了
Yes.
谢尔顿  到底怎么啦
Sheldon, what's going on?
我读了他的研究...
I read his research, and...
他的成果超过我好几百条街
it's leaps and bounds ahead of mine.
这也意味着  学校里第一聪明的物理学家
Which means the mommy of the smartest physicist
原来不是我的妈的儿子
at the university is not my mommy as I had thought.
而是他妈的儿子
It's his mommy.
谢尔顿  真希望能为你做点什么
Sheldon, I wish there was something I could do
让你开心点的事情
to make you feel better.
我能给你个安慰拥抱吗
May I offer you a consoling hug?
我都没东西能损失了  当然行
What do we have to lose?
感觉如何
How's that?
感觉像是被大蟒蛇勒住了
I feel like I'm being strangled by a boa constrictor.
谁让你松手的
Why'd you stop?
谢尔顿  快点  要迟到了
Come on, Sheldon! We're going to be late!
我今天去不了  我生病了
I can't go in today. I'm sick.
你才没生病
You're not sick.
你只是不想面对克莱皮克
You just don't want to face Kripke.
是真的  你看
No, look.
128华氏度[约53.3摄氏度]
128.
你看吧
See?
你把这玩意浸茶里了吗
What did you do, put this in your tea?
不是吧
Oh, dear.
现在我笨得连你都蒙不了了
Now I'm not even smarter than you.
谢尔顿  你不是比克莱皮克笨啦
Sheldon, Kripke's not smarter than you.
你只是思路错了
You just got stuck on a wrong path.
爱因斯坦也这样过啊
Happened to Einstein.
他被统一场论困扰了好几十年
He got stuck on the unified field theory for decades.
别跟我说什么爱因斯坦
Oh, don't play the Einstein card.
他成功的前提是  当时的所有人毛都不懂
His great breakthroughs happened when no one knew anything.
所以发现什么都能算是大突破
So everything was a great breakthrough.
谢尔顿·李·库珀
Sheldon Lee Cooper,
我没时间听你胡扯
I do not have time for this nonsense.
现在赶紧给我穿衣服  上车
Now, go put your clothes on, get in the car,
跟我上班去
and lets go to work.
别激动啊  仁兄
All right, geez.
瞧你这小爆脾气
What a grouch.
我是怎么做到的
How did I do that?
我得记住刚才是怎么做到的
I got to remember how I did that.
你有没有意识到  拥有这台3-D打印机
Do you realize, by owning a 3-D printer,
我们就能夺回生产过程
we are reclaiming the manufacturing process
并抢回中国血汗工厂工人的工作
and taking jobs back from sweatshops in China?
这玩意本身就是中国制造的
I think this thing was made in China.
那我们也没办法了
Eh, what can you do?
完成了
Ooh, I-I think it's done.
成功了
It worked!
我们造了个哨子
We printed a whistle.
酷毙了
Amazing.
你知道这东西在派对用品店里
You realize these things go for 25 cents a pop
一个卖25美分吧
at a party store.
而且仅用三小时就做好了
And we made it in only three hours.
声音和店里卖的一模一样
Sounds just like store-bought.
你摆个超级英雄的姿势
Okay, give me a superhero pose,
我把你扫描到电脑
and I will scan you into the computer
好做出你的模型人偶
for your action figure.
要是我身材好点就好了
Oh, I wish I was in better shape.
别收腹了
Stop holding your stomach in.
我会用电脑给你安上六块诱人腹肌
I'll give you a six-pack with the computer.
好的  太好了
Oh, okay, great.
我能有瓦尔·基尔默在《蝙蝠侠》中的身材
Now I can look like Val Kilmer as Batman
蝙蝠侠扮演者
而不用是他现在这身材
instead of Val Kilmer as he looks today.
你还是稍微收一下腹吧
All right, you can suck it in a little bit.
库珀  我们得聊聊
Cooper, we have a problem.
你的研究可真是没
Your work is really not
达到我原以为的水准啊
at a level I expected it to be.
我知道
I know.
尽情嘲笑我吧
Go ahead, mock me.
用点简单的词  免得我听不懂
Just use small words so I understand.
别跟我装傻
Don't play dumb with me.
你我都知道你的问题在哪里
We both know what your problem is.
是吗
We do?
你有个女朋友
You have a girlfriend.
所以呢
So?
换我的话  专业水平也会降低
So my work would suffer, too,
谁叫你每天巫山云雨乐不思蜀呢
if I was getting laid all the time.
没错
Yes.
就是因为这个
That is the reason.
我的专业水准降低  就是因为
My work is suffering because of...
巫山云雨乐不思蜀
all the laid I'm getting.
你这个走运的混蛋
You lucky bastard.
我能说什么呢
What can I say, you know?
她很享受我的生殖器
She enjoys my genitals.
我每天晚上都让她欲仙欲死
I am giving them to her on a nightly basis.
少显摆了
Okay, stop bragging.
你有一些很棒的见解
You had some brilliant insights in here,
但如果我们要成功的话
but if we're gonna make this work,
你得集中注意力  多加努力才行
you need to buckle down and focus.
我会尽力而为的
I'll do what I can.
但这并非易事
But it's not going to be easy,
因为我和艾米在一起时
because when I'm with Amy
我们的关键部位磨磨蹭蹭...
and our bathing suit areas mush together...
真是让人无法自拔啊
is it boy howdy, is it magic.
真好  你回来了
Oh, good, you're home.
我给你准备了小惊喜
Got a little surprise for you.
是什么
What?
和我这位小朋友打个招呼吧
Say hello to my little friend.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
真是太可爱了
That's so cute.
我真没想到还能有更小版的你啊
I didn't think there could be a smaller version of you.
是吧是吧
I know, right?
多亏有照片
And, thanks to photographs
还有3D塑造工艺
and some little 3-D modeling,
新娘驾到咯
here comes the bride.
华仔  我好喜欢啊
Oh, Howie, I love these.
我就知道你会的
I thought you might.
这东西贵吗
Were they expensive?
一分钱没花  我自己做的
Didn't cost a thing. I made them myself.
-怎么做的  -库萨帕里和我
- How? - Koothrappali and I
花五千块买了个二手3-D打印机
bought a used 3-D printer for $5,000.
五千块买了几个娃娃
$5,000 for a couple of dolls?
你吃错药了吗
Are you out of your mind?
这可不是几个娃娃
Not just a couple of dolls.
我们想要多少  就能做多少
For as many dolls as we want.
还能做哨子呢
And whistles.
你这样花钱如流水的时候
At any point, did it dawn on you to talk to me
有想过要跟我通报一声吗
about spending this kind of money?
现在想到了
It's kind of dawning on me now.
简直难以置信
I don't believe you!
华仔  我们没钱买这样的垃圾
Howie, we can't afford to waste money on junk like this.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我们挣了那么多的钱
We make plenty of money.
我挣了很多钱
I make plenty of money!
你赚得塞牙缝都不够
You make peanuts!
是的  但现在我们是夫妻了
Yes, but we're married now.
这意味着  你生病时
That means, when you get sick,
我会照顾你
I take care of you.
你挣很多钱时
And when you make a bunch of money,
我可以买东西
I get to buy stuff.
你不喜欢也没办法
Sorry if you don't like it,
爱情就是这样
but that's how love works.
不  爱情是这样
No, here's how love works.
要么你退回机器
You're gonna return the machine,
要么你就打印出一套女性私密部位
or you can print out a working set of lady parts
跟那"睡"去吧
and sleep with those.
我的天  你居然还真想啊
Oh, my God! Are you actually thinking about it?
好吧  我不太明白
All right, I don't understand.
你为什么不跟克莱皮克说实话
Why didn't you just tell Kripke the truth?
说实话会让我很没面子
Because the truth made me look bad,
相反  荒谬又无耻的谎言令我面上有光
whereas a ridiculous bald-faced lie makes me look good.
总之  如果克莱皮克问起
Anyway, if Kripke asks,
跟他说  我与艾米的行房是频繁的
tell him my coitus with Amy is frequent,
激烈的   创造力十足的
intense and whimsically inventive.
我行房时有创造力十足吗
Is my coitus whimsically inventive?
我在公共厕所的墙上就是这样写的
That is what I write on the bathroom walls.
要寻找创造力十足的一夜激情
"For a whimsically inventive time,
请致电莱纳德·霍夫斯塔德
call Leonard Hofstadter."
我知道你在开玩笑  不过我不介意啦
I know you're joking, but I'd be okay with that.
-谢尔顿  问你个问题好吗  -请便
- Sheldon, can I ask you a question? - Of course.
你会跟艾米上床吗
You ever going to sleep with Amy?
这是相当私人的问题
That's awfully personal.
我们不问谢尔顿这样的问题
We don't ask Sheldon things like that.
也许你不能问  我能
Maybe you don't; I do.
到底怎么回事
What's the deal?
现在大学里风传
Well, word around the university
我给予了她的性器官到位的撞击
is I'm giving her sex organs a proper jostling.
得了  说真的
All right, come on, be serious.
你们已经交往很长时间了
Look, you guys have been going out a long time.
很明显她希望
She would clearly like
与你发生性爱关系
to have a physical relationship with you,
你到底在干嘛
so what are you doing?
好吧  废话说完了
All right, we're down the rabbit hole.
你到底在干嘛
What are you doing?
首先  我相当喜欢艾米
Well, first of all, I'm quite fond of Amy.
那有什么问题
Then what's the problem?
佩妮
Penny...
我这辈子  其他人觉得
all my life, I have been uncomfortable
轻而易举的身体接触
with the sort of physical contact
我都觉得不自在
that comes easily to others--
握手  拥抱
hand-shaking, hugging,
前列腺检查
prostate exams.
但我在努力改变  知道吗
But I'm working on it, you know?
最近  我还给艾米的胸口擦了感冒止咳膏呢
Just recently, I had to put VapoRub on Amy's chest.
一年前  这是无法想像的事
A year ago, that would have been unthinkable.
现在你明白了  我被迫给你擦时是什么滋味
Now you know how I feel when I have to put it on you.
好了  等等
Okay. Hang on.
你是说有一天  你与艾米
Are you saying someday you and Amy might...
会有亲密接触吗
actually get physical?
有这个可能性
It's a possibility.
我的天
Oh, my God!
谢尔顿  我知道对你来说不容易
Sheldon, I know this wasn't easy for you,
我真的很高兴你愿意聊这个话题
and I'm really glad we could have this conversation.
别客气
Oh, yeah.
你确定要这样做吗
Are you sure you want to do this?
放弃3-D打印机的一半所有权
Give up your half of the 3-D printer?
是的
Yes.
麻烦你写上伯纳黛特的名字
And can you please make that out to Bernadette?
我从联名账户中除名了
I was taken off the joint account
等我了解金钱的价值后才能回归
until I learn the value of money.
太残忍了
Wow, that's harsh.
还用说吗
Tell me about it.
你不吃午餐吗
Aren't you gonna eat lunch?
我的饭钱都花在口袋妖怪卡上了
Nah, I blew my food allowance on Pokemon cards.
等式两端相等
Well, the equation balances,
但是算法不够简洁
but it's certainly not elegant.
无所谓  昨晚你又爽了吧
Whatever. You get any last night?
是的
Yes.
给了她猛烈地一发咩
Gave it to her good, huh?
不  是给了她升天的一发
No, I gave it to her well.
好了  这里  我在想
Now, over here, I was thinking
湍流可以减少  只要我们...
the turbulence could be reduced if we just put...
随便啦
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
她是一丝不挂  还是穿着内衣半遮半掩
Was she naked, or was she wearing lingerie?
我没注意
I didn't notice.
你怎么会没注意
How could you not notice?
我忙于
I was too busy
挤压她身体的所有欲望部位
squishing all the desirable parts of her body.
我听得好嗨啊  库珀
Ah, you're killing me, Cooper!
可以继续谈工作吗
Can we get back to work?
当然  当然
Sure, sure, sure.
你们有用过玩具吗[性用具]
You guys ever use any toys?
玩具
Toys?
我床边放着一个火箭模型
I do have a model rocket next to my bed.
火箭  你个死变态
A rocket? You're a freak!
太合我胃口了
I love it!